<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--Created using XmlSitemapGenerator.org - Free HTML, RSS and XML sitemap generator-->
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes | Home</title>
    <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com</link>
    <description />
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/</guid>
      <title>Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes | Home</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/</link>
      <description>Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes. The online home of Chris Roberts a Business Minded, Computational Biological Scientist with a passion for learning and furthering his understanding of the universe, life, technology, himself and others. An online portfolio of Chris' Scientific, IT and Business Skills, his academic career including undergraduate bachelor of science in Genetics and Human Health and his post graduate masters of research in post genomic science. A site to demonstrate Chris' Web design and web development skills hand coded in html and css</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/bsc-genetics-and-human-health.html</guid>
      <title>BSc Genetics &amp; Human Health | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/bsc-genetics-and-human-health.html</link>
      <description>Christopher John Roberts' bachelor of science Genetics and Human Health BSc studies at Aberystwyth University including his Lab based Dissertation Project: A Proteomic Study of Resistance and Susceptibility to Schistosome Infection in Biomphalaria glabrata. List of modules studied for his undergraduate biological science degree in genetics and human health, including, molecular genetics, functional genomics, gene expression, evolution and molecular biology</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/cv.html</guid>
      <title>CV | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/cv.html</link>
      <description>CV of Christopher John Roberts a Business Minded, Computational Biological Scientist. Academic career bachelor of science in genetics and human health, masters of research in post genomic science. Business skills as information comunication technology ICT recruitment consultant</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/hobbies.html</guid>
      <title>Hobbies | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/hobbies.html</link>
      <description>Christopher John Roberts' Hobbies, including Swing Dancing and Photography.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/proteomics.html</guid>
      <title>Proteomics | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/proteomics.html</link>
      <description>Bachelor of Science in Genetics and Human Health final year project a laboratory based dissertation: A Proteomic Study of Resistance and Susceptibility to Schistosome Infection in Biomphalaria glabrata. Abstract from the laboratory research project along with the aims and objectives, materials and methods, results and discussion for the Proteomic Study of Resistance and Susceptibility to Schistosome Infection in Biomphalaria glabrata by Chris Roberts at Aberystwyth University</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/technical-meetups.html</guid>
      <title>Tech Meetups | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/technical-meetups.html</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/sitemap.html</guid>
      <title>Sitemap | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/sitemap.html</link>
      <description>Sitemap for the home of Christopher John Roberts . . . </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/7_references.pdf</guid>
      <title>7_references.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/7_references.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/javascript/javascript-projects.html</guid>
      <title>Javascript Projects | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/javascript/javascript-projects.html</link>
      <description>Javascipt projects by Christopher John Roberts</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/about-christopher-john-roberts.html</guid>
      <title>About | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/about-christopher-john-roberts.html</link>
      <description>About Christopher John Roberts . . . </description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/mres-post-genomic-science.html</guid>
      <title>Post Genomic Science - MRes | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/mres-post-genomic-science.html</link>
      <description>Chris' Post Genomic Science MRes studies at the University of Liverpool</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/ecommerce-executive.html</guid>
      <title>Ecommerce Executive | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/ecommerce-executive.html</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/cell-biology.html</guid>
      <title>Cell Biology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/cell-biology.html</link>
      <description>Cell Biology Module studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Evolution of Cell, compartmentalisation, chloroplasts, mitochondria, plasma membranes, cell walls, cell junctions and communication, cytoskeleton, nucleus, DNA, RNA, robosomes, Golgi apparatus, Lysosome, Social behaviour of cells and multicellualrity</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/8_appendicies.pdf</guid>
      <title>8_appendicies.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/8_appendicies.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/1_abstract_and_contents.pdf</guid>
      <title>1_abstract_and_contents.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/1_abstract_and_contents.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introduction-biochemistry.html</guid>
      <title>Introductory Biochemistry | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introduction-biochemistry.html</link>
      <description>Introduction Biochemistry studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Amino acids and proteins, mono-, di- and poly-saccharides and lipids, nucleotides and nucleic acids and the relationship of structure to function, chemistry , stereochemistry, Monosaccharides, simple sugars, carbohydrates,  di- and polysaccharides, Amino acids, peptide bonding, protein composition, Saponifiable and unsaponifiable lipids, fats, oils, phospholipids as the basis of lipid bilayer membranes, with unsaponifiable lipid (terpenoid) and lipophilic protein inclusions, nucleotides , nucleic acids, hydrogen bonding and its importance in the complementary base-pairing in DNA</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/human-biology-and-health.html</guid>
      <title>Human Biology &amp; Health | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/human-biology-and-health.html</link>
      <description>Human Biology and Health studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. how biotic and abiotic factors impact upon human health and fitness, organization and development of the human body, and include fertilisation, embryology, development, ageing, evolution, blood, circulatory system, immune system, skeletal system, muscular system, respiratory system, urinary system, reproductive system, nervous system, sensory system, endocrine system, digestive system and nutrition. Chris Roberts.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/human-genetics-and-medical-biochemistry.html</guid>
      <title>Human Genetics &amp; Medical Biochemistry | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/human-genetics-and-medical-biochemistry.html</link>
      <description>Human Genetics and Medical Biochemistry studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Genetics and medical biochemistry in the context of human perspectives, biochemistry, immunology and genetics, genomics, bioinformatics, human genome project, human gene mapping and human gene therapy, heredity, the cell cycle, mitosis, meiosis, gametogenesis and fertilization in human development, including the phenomenon of imprinting human chromosome structure,  sex-linked genes, sex determination, variations, aberrations, mutations, linkage and crossing over. The human genome, molecular diagnosis, genetic screening and counseling, prenatal diagnosis and potential gene therapy of human diseases, immunogenetics, antibody production, DNA fingerprinting (paternity test, forensic application and sex identification of unborn), the future of human gene therapy approaches, the merits of human genome programme and ethics pertaining to human genetics and society.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/4_materials_and_methods.pdf</guid>
      <title>4_materials_and_methods.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/4_materials_and_methods.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/2_introduction.pdf</guid>
      <title>2_introduction.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/2_introduction.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/gametes-cells-and-animal-development.html</guid>
      <title>Gametes Cells &amp; Animal Development | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/gametes-cells-and-animal-development.html</link>
      <description>Gametes Cells and Animal Development studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Cellular aspects of reproduction and gamete formation,  embryo development, aging and cancer in context of evolution, animal development from gamete formation to maturity, reproduction, ageing and cancer in the context of cellular physiology, eukaryotic cell-cycle, apoptosis, Gametogenesis, leading to fertilization mechanisms, cell adhesion and motility, growth factors, extracellular matrix, neural crest movements, cleavage and gastrulation, induction, tissue communication, Interaction between ectoderm and mesoderm, limb development, homeobox genes, aging, oncogenesis.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/exploring-genetics.html</guid>
      <title>Exploring Genetics | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/exploring-genetics.html</link>
      <description>Exploring Genetics studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. genes ,chromosomes and genomes. Benzer's fine structure analysis of the rII locus of T4 bacteriophage, complementation, recombination, colinearity of genes and proteins, and the molecular structure of eukaryotic genes. Genomic Environment of the Gene, andem gene rays, mobile genetic elements and centromeres, Meiosis and Recombination of the Gene, chiasmatype theory, Gene conversion, reciprocal and non-reciprocal recombination, double-strand break repair model of molecular recombination. Mitotic recombination, Chromosome Environment of the Gene,chromosome number, morphology, nomenclature and karyotyping, allopolyploidy, Deficiencies, duplications, inversions and translocations, evolution of sex, clonal reproduction, breeding systems and sex determination. Non-Mendelian Inheritance: Cytoplasmic inheritance. endosymbionts, gene transfer and conflicts between cell compartments, epigenetics, including methylation and post-transcriptional gene silencing, and supernumerary chromosomes</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/5_results.pdf</guid>
      <title>5_results.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/5_results.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introductory-genetics.html</guid>
      <title>Genetics | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introductory-genetics.html</link>
      <description>Introductory Genetics studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Understanding and developing a conceptual framework based on the transmission, the structure and the function of the genetic material. Genetics is studied at different levels of organisation from the molecular, through cells and individuals, up to populations and to evolutionary changes. Transmission genetics in eukaryotes, Nuclear division at mitosis, karyotypes and chromosome complements, gene segregation and the concepts of dominance, the testcross and allelic interaction,  independent segregation, recombination and other aspects of gene interaction, Meiosis, Linkage, and intra-chromosomal recombination, DNA structure, genes and proteins and the nature of the genetic code, Gene action is reviewed through transcription and translation, DNA replication and its relationship to the cell cycle and to chromosome structure, Mutation frequency, gene mutation, chromosome mutation, gene frequencies, change in gene frequencies and micro-evolution. Sex-linked inheritance, and quantitative genetics and modes of selection in eukaryotes, molecular genetics, recombinant DNA and the regulation of gene expression in prokaryotes</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/gene-expression-and-developmental-genetics.html</guid>
      <title>Gene Expression &amp; Developmental Genetics | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/gene-expression-and-developmental-genetics.html</link>
      <description>Gene Expression and Developmental Genetics studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Signaling mechanisms, gene expression and cell signaling, eukaryotic cell cellular development and tissue morphogenesis, cell adhesion and motility in development, Differential regulation of gene expression, signalling cascades, genes and cell-to-cell communication, gene expression, cell signalling and cellular development, Regulation of transcription, mRNA processing, translation and post-translational processing</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/informatics-for-life-sciences.html</guid>
      <title>Informatics For Life Sciences | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/informatics-for-life-sciences.html</link>
      <description>Informatics For Life Sciences studied during MRes Advanced Biological Sciences. Informatics, bioinformatics, database, research, BLAST (Basic Local Alignment Search Tool), PSI-BLAST, sequence analysis, phylogenetics, modelling proteins, modelling pathways, ecosystems, evolution.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/chemical-basis-of-biological-processes.html</guid>
      <title>Chemical Basis Of Biological Processes | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/chemical-basis-of-biological-processes.html</link>
      <description>Chemical Basis of Biological Processes studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Biological molecules, Chemistry, bonding in organic molecules, structural and geometric isomerism in organic carbon compounds, carbohydrates and peptides, energy changes during reactions, energetics, enzymes in biological processes, pH, acids and bases, buffers, radioactivity, isotopes, radioactive emissions</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/awards.html</guid>
      <title>Awards | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/awards.html</link>
      <description>Awards presented to Christopher John Roberts such as IBERS (Instituate of Biological, Environmental and Rural Science) Directors Prize, Faculty of Science Laboratory Research Bursary, Merit and Scholarship Awards for University of Wales, Aberystwyth University and Bangor University</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it-home.html</guid>
      <title>IT | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it-home.html</link>
      <description>IT experience of Christopher John Roberts, including his information computer technology, computational, programming and coding skills. Chris' time spend as a IT recruitment consultant for IT developers, programmers and coders and Chris' skills of coding, programming, web development, web design, SEO, HTML, CSS, perl scripts, databases, MySQL and SQL. Teaching experience as a digital champion engaging people with technology and the internet, teaching computer skills</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/business-skills.html</guid>
      <title>Business Skills | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/business-skills.html</link>
      <description>Business experience of Christopher John Roberts. Chris' sales, business and consultant skills developed in a specialist IT recruitment role. Closing pieces of business, managing expectations of clients through informed communication, selling, objection handling, margin and rate justification, negotiation, relationship management. Business and Sales courses and training attended such as selling success</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/functional-annotation-of-proteins.html</guid>
      <title>Functional Annotation Of Proteins | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/functional-annotation-of-proteins.html</link>
      <description>Bioinformatics research project at The Institute of Biological, Environmental and Rural Sciences IBERS. Building the Brachypodium – Poaceae Bridge: Anchoring Brachypodium Genomes to Rice Pseudomolecules by Chris Roberts at IBS Institute of Biological Sciences and IGER Institute of Biological, Environmental and Rural Sciences at Aberystwyth University</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/scientific-skills.html</guid>
      <title>Scientific Skills | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/scientific-skills.html</link>
      <description>Christopher John Roberts Scientific skills and experience, including literature research, data gathering, formulating hypothesis, statistical analysis of data and critical evaluation developed during his bachelor of science in genetics and human health</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/star-wars-character-profiles.js</guid>
      <title>star-wars-character-profiles.js</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/star-wars-character-profiles.js</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/3_aims_and_objectives.pdf</guid>
      <title>3_aims_and_objectives.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/3_aims_and_objectives.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/coin-toss.js</guid>
      <title>coin-toss.js</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/coin-toss.js</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/how-many-people-in-space.html</guid>
      <title>How Many People In Space?</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/how-many-people-in-space.html</link>
      <description>Returns how many people are currently in space</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/coin-toss.html</guid>
      <title>Coin Toss</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/coin-toss.html</link>
      <description>Simulate a coin toss</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/An_Integrated_Approach_to_Function_Annotation_in_the_Histidine_Phosphatase_Superfamily_Christopher_John_Roberts_mres_report.pdf</guid>
      <title>An_Integrated_Approach_to_Function_Annotation_in_the_Histidine_Phosphatase_Superfamily_Christopher_John_Roberts_mres_report.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/An_Integrated_Approach_to_Function_Annotation_in_the_Histidine_Phosphatase_Superfamily_Christopher_John_Roberts_mres_report.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/ecology.html</guid>
      <title>Ecology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/ecology.html</link>
      <description>Ecology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. ecosystem, ecology, ecological hierarchy, ecological organisation, biosphere, transfer of energy between different trophic level cycling of nutrients within systems, abiotic factors, biotic factors, predation and competition, resource utilisation by species, niches, adaption, ecotypic variation, autecology and succession</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/6_discussion.pdf</guid>
      <title>6_discussion.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/6_discussion.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/quantitative-biology-and-information-technology.html</guid>
      <title>QB &amp; Information Technology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/quantitative-biology-and-information-technology.html</link>
      <description>Quantitative Biology and Information Technology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Information Technology, Spreadsheet software, excel, minitab, database management, image analysis, HTML CSS webpages, Quantitative Biology, Calculus, Biological Statistics, Hypothesis testing, ANOVA</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/programming-for-life-sciences.html</guid>
      <title>Programming For Life Sciences | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/programming-for-life-sciences.html</link>
      <description>Programming for Life Sciences studied during MRes Advanced Biological Sciences. Programming, scripting language, Perl, Perl scripts, bioinformatics, BLAST, object-oriented programming, Bioperl, variables, strings, conditionals, arrays, looping structures, hashes, subroutines, command line arguments, web programming, programming code, relational database, MySQL, regular expressions</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/</guid>
      <title>Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes | Home</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/</link>
      <description>Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes. The online home of Chris Roberts a Business Minded, Computational Biological Scientist with a passion for learning and furthering his understanding of the universe, life, technology, himself and others. An online portfolio of Chris' Scientific, IT and Business Skills, his academic career including undergraduate bachelor of science in Genetics and Human Health and his post graduate masters of research in post genomic science. A site to demonstrate Chris' Web design and web development skills hand coded in html and css</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/molecular-genetics-of-microbes.html</guid>
      <title>Molecular Genetics Of Microbes | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/molecular-genetics-of-microbes.html</link>
      <description>Description of Molecular Genetics of Microbes Module studied during BSc Genetics and Human Health. Mechanistic basis and biological significance of genetic exchange between bacteria, physical and genetic maps, genetic systems of both Gram-negative and Gram-positive bacteria, how bacteria respond to environmental changes, genetics of bacteria and their viruses, classical and molecular genetic techniques, the ways in which bacteria respond to different mutagenic agent, DNA repair, Genetic exchange (transformation, transduction and conjugation), homologous recombination, biology of plasmids and their use in genetic engineering, mechanisms whereby plasmids replicate and are transmitted from cell to cell and those involved in determining plasmid copy number and compatibility, Mechanisms of transposition, illegitimate and site-specific recombination, transposable elements and reporter genes for investigating gene expression, Transposable elements, bacterial cell cycle, DNA replication and cell division</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introductory-microbiology.html</guid>
      <title>Microbiology | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introductory-microbiology.html</link>
      <description>Microbiology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Diversity of life forms within the eukaryotic and prokaryotic micro-organisms, the ways in which micro-organisms adapt to, and affect, their environment, how micro-organisms interact with other organisms, the diversity of a form, the nutritional versatility and the environmental adaptability of micro-organisms, non-photosynthetic bacteria, diversity of morphology, cell structure and reproduction. Fungi economic importance, diversity of form and function in the photosynthetic micro-organisms, photosynthetic prokaryotes (bacteria and cyanobacteria) and photosynthetic eukaryotes (algae)diversity of form, genetic systems and life strategies</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/information-technology-and-quantitative-biology.html</guid>
      <title>Information Technology &amp; QB | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/information-technology-and-quantitative-biology.html</link>
      <description>Information Technology and Quantitative Biology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Word-processing and spreadsheet tasks, numerical data in the analysis of the results of biological experiments, numerical, information technology, study, laboratory, time-management and communication skills, as well as general biological knowledge needed by a modern biologist, storage of data in files, file management, network uses, printing, as well as effective use of a graphical user interface, mathematical concepts set in a background of handling biological data, types of numbers; significant figures; scientific notation; units - conversion from one level to another (including Standard SI units); logarithms, converting from number to log and back again; exponents; tables and graphs; concepts of dilution series; percentages and proportions; basic algebra; accuracy and precision in reporting results; the straight line, second and third degree polynomial functions, the exponential and power functions, allometry in plants and animals; elements of probability theory; samples and populations; relative frequency histograms and probability density curves; measures of location- mode, median, mean, measures of spread - inter-quartile range, variance, standard deviation, coefficient of variation, coefficient of skewness; the normal, Poisson and binomial distributions</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introduction-to-vertebrate-zoology.html</guid>
      <title>Vertebrate Zoology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introduction-to-vertebrate-zoology.html</link>
      <description>Introduction to Vertebrate Zoology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Morphology and anatomy, adaptive features, vertebrate evolution and phylogeny, vertebrate classification, vertebrate design, diversity of body form and function, inter-relationships., evolutionary history, structure and physiology, amphibians, locomotion, respiration, osmoregulation and reproduction. Urodele and anuran metamorphosis, life histories, biochemical changes (excretion, haemoglobin) and hormonal control (role of thyroid, pituitary and hypothalamus), reptiles, structural, physiological and reproductive adaptations, origins and the structural and physiological characteristics of the mammals, adaptive radiation and geographical distribution</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/functional-genomics.html</guid>
      <title>Functional Genomics | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/functional-genomics.html</link>
      <description>Functional Genomics studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Genomics and related databases to analyse gene and genome inter-relationships, structural relationships of proteins, model systems for functional genomics, transcriptome, proteome and metabolome analysis. Computational methods used to interpret functional genomics data, high throughput screening and forced evolution methodologies, biological data analysis and interpretation, bioinformatics, database access, sequence analysis, protein classification and functional assignment, the human genome project in society, Genome mapping strategies, Model systems for functional genomics, Post genomics technologies, Protein-protein interactions, Advanced protein modelling and secondary structure prediction, HighThroughput Screening, Systems Biology</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/population-and-conservation-genetics.html</guid>
      <title>Population &amp; Conservation Genetics | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/population-and-conservation-genetics.html</link>
      <description>Description of Population and Conservation Genetics Module studied during BSc Genetics and Human Health. Principles of population genetics, the application of population genetics, phylogeography and phylogenetic methods to conservation, the relevance of transgenic technology to agriculture, conservation and medicine, population genetics and its relevance to conservation, molecular techniques used for management of rare and threatened species, population genetics, phylogeographic and phylogenetic approaches used for management of particular endangered species, modern transgenic technology, Molecular markers, population genetics, Hardy Weinberg &amp; changes in gene frequency, Non-random mating and the consequences of inbreeding on conservation / Metapopulations and population dynamics, How the loss of biodiversity &amp; genetic diversity affects ecosystem function &amp; environment, Phylogeographic / phylogenetic approaches to conservation and management, taxonomic units, In situ conservation, extinction and preservation, Ex situ conservation, Gene banks - preserving genetic diversity for conservation / Reproductive technology, Transgenic technology and its application to conservation</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/research-methods-and-applications-in-biological-sciences.html</guid>
      <title>Research Methods &amp; Applications In Biological Sciences | Chris Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/research-methods-and-applications-in-biological-sciences.html</link>
      <description>Research Methods and Applications in Biological Sciences studied during MRes Advanced Biological Sciences. research, develop hypotheses, design experiments, test hypotheses, critically review, legal, moral, ethics, ethical, Synthesise information, experimental design and hypothesis testing, research ethics, popular science writing and public understanding of science, mathematical modelling, genomic technologies, transcriptomics and arrays, proteomics, molecular ecology, meta analysis.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/honours-special-study.html</guid>
      <title>Honours Special Study | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/honours-special-study.html</link>
      <description>Honours Special Study studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health by Chris Roberts.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/what-is-my-ip-address.js</guid>
      <title>what-is-my-ip-address.js</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/what-is-my-ip-address.js</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/webpage-scraper.html</guid>
      <title>Webpage Scraper</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/webpage-scraper.html</link>
      <description>Scrape a webpage</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/how-many-people-in-space.js</guid>
      <title>how-many-people-in-space.js</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/how-many-people-in-space.js</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/webpage-scraper.js</guid>
      <title>webpage-scraper.js</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/javascript-projects-resources/js/webpage-scraper.js</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/star-wars-character-profiles.html</guid>
      <title>Star Wars Character Profiles</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/star-wars-character-profiles.html</link>
      <description>Search Star Wars Character Profiles</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/health-and-the-food-chain.html</guid>
      <title>Health &amp; The Food Chain | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/health-and-the-food-chain.html</link>
      <description>Health and the Food Chain Module studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Food in governing human health, production, quality and distribution of food, quality of food, human resources and impact on the environment, Origin and evolution of food animals and plants, Animal care and welfare, intensive breeding, breeding strategies, plant breeding, food production, molecular methods of crop improvement, GMOs and risk assessment, organic farming, Development, productivity and sustainability of crop production, strategies of pest control, Food quality, microbiology, probiotics, allergy, adulteration, contamination, labelling, authentication and food standards, food processing and additives, Nutrition, nutritional values, malnutrition, obesity, eating disorders, food distribution, fair trade and meeting the global needs for food.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/post-genomic-bioinformatics.html</guid>
      <title>Post Genomic Bioinformatics | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/post-genomic-bioinformatics.html</link>
      <description>Post-Genomic Bioinformatics studied during MRes Advanced Biological Sciences. genomic, transcriptomic and proteomic technologies, bioinformatics, research, genome bioinformatics, proteome bioinformatics, sequence alignment: programs and algorithms, protein secondary sequence databases, linux, genomic analysis, proteome, proteomic analysis, modelling of proteins, secondary databases of protein structure, protein structure informed functional annotation, next-generation genomic methods, de novo assembly, proteomics and bioinformatics for identifying proteins by mass spectrometry, label-based quantification strategies including SILAC and iTRAQ labelling strategies, identifying proteins using Mascot search engine, iTRAQ quantification using OpenMS</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science-home.html</guid>
      <title>Science | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science-home.html</link>
      <description>Scientific experience of Christopher John Roberts including his bachelor of science in genetics and human health and masters of research in post genomic science. His university biological science projects including a laboratory based Proteomic Study of Resistance and Susceptibility to Schistosome Infection in Biomphalaria glabrata and a Bioinformatics research project, a study Anchoring Brachypodium Genomes to Rice Pseudomolecules. Proteomics, Genomics, Bioinformatics and his interest in Origin of Life, Molecular Genetics, Evolution, Genomics Aging and Bioinformatics</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/genomics.html</guid>
      <title>Genomics | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/genomics.html</link>
      <description>Bioinformatics research project at The Institute of Biological, Environmental and Rural Sciences IBERS. Building the Brachypodium – Poaceae Bridge: Anchoring Brachypodium Genomes to Rice Pseudomolecules by Chris Roberts at IBS Institute of Biological Sciences and IGER Institute of Biological, Environmental and Rural Sciences at Aberystwyth University</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/contact-christopher-john-roberts.html</guid>
      <title>Contact | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/contact-christopher-john-roberts.html</link>
      <description>Contact information for Christopher John Roberts, including Chris' email address, phone number and linkedin, twitter and facebook accounts</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/websites.html</guid>
      <title>Websites | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/websites.html</link>
      <description>Websites Chris Roberts has worked on and contributed his web development, programming and coding skills to. His knowledge of HTML, CSS, WISIWIG, CMS, Weebly, Web Design, User Experience, SEO, Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools and Google AdWords to design and develop websites. Christopher John Roberts ICT skills showcased online</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/digital-champion.html</guid>
      <title>Digital Champion | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/digital-champion.html</link>
      <description>Chris Roberts training as a Digital Champion for Get Online Wrexham Flintshire part of an overall Digital Inclusion Strategy from the Welsh Government, helping people engage with ICT, computers, technology and the internet. Christopher John roberts' role is to teach information computer technology skills</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/it-skills.html</guid>
      <title>IT Skills | Christopher John Roberts BSc (Hons) MRes</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/it/it-skills.html</link>
      <description>Chris Roberts ICT information computer technology skills from development, coding and programming to specialist software. His Web Development skills including HTML CSS MySQL SQL queries and SEO to Perl script and use of Statistical Analysis Software such as Minitab</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/brachypodium/brachypodium_proposal.pdf</guid>
      <title>brachypodium_proposal.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/brachypodium/brachypodium_proposal.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/plant-biology.html</guid>
      <title>Plant Biology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/plant-biology.html</link>
      <description>Description of Plant Biology Module studied during BSc Genetics and Human Health. Plant form, anatomy, physiology, developoment and diversity, plant taxonomy, eco-physiology, evolution and biotechnology, anatomical features of plant specimens at the macroscopic and microscopic levels. Plant structures, development, functional processes and diversity. morphologies and internal organization of plant organs, plant anatomy, physiological mechanisms, transport systems including the function of xylem and the ascent of sap and the association of phloem with the movement of assimilates; energy flow and photosynthetic processes; mineral nutrition and the effects of toxic metals; and water as a limiting factor. Plant growth, development, and movements, roles of plant hormones</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/what-is-my-ip-address.html</guid>
      <title>What Is My IP Address?</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/what-is-my-ip-address.html</link>
      <description>Returns your IP address</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/project.html</guid>
      <title>MRes Research Project | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-mres/project.html</link>
      <description>MRes Research Project studied during MRes Advanced Biological Sciences.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introduction-to-invertebrate-zoology.html</guid>
      <title>Invertebrate Zoology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/introduction-to-invertebrate-zoology.html</link>
      <description>Introduction to Invertebrate Zoology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Invertebrate design, diversity of body form and function, invertebrate design and classification, inter-relationships.  triploblastic - the germ layer theory; the development and significance of body cavities; metamerism; symmetry; cleavage patterns. Protostome and deuterostome lines of evolution, Arthropodization - intermittent growth patterns, Dyar's law, growth cycles. Moulting , adaptive radiation, symmetry, diversity of body form, the endoskeleton, sponges; polymorphism of cnidarians; diversity, form and function, and adaptive radiation of the major phyla,  morphology and anatomy, invertebrate phylogeny, invertebrate classification</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/project.html</guid>
      <title>Genetics &amp; Human Health Project | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/project.html</link>
      <description>Project studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Research, data collection, data recording and evaluation of data, research protocol, experiments / make observations / critically assess the literature, investigation, analyse and present data and observation, scientific writing</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/applied-molecular-biology.html</guid>
      <title>Applied Molecular Biology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/applied-molecular-biology.html</link>
      <description>Applied Molecular Biology studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Molecular Biology - understanding biological processes at the molecular level. DNA, RNA, Protein transgenic organisms, FISH, GISH, DNA cloning vectors, PCR, RNA splicing, cDNA libraries, protein-protein interactions, marker genes, transgenics.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/principles-of-animal-physiology.html</guid>
      <title>Animal Physiology | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/principles-of-animal-physiology.html</link>
      <description>Description of Principles of Animal Physiology studied during BSc Genetics and Human Health. Physiological principles underpining animal activity and behaviour homeostasis and feedback control, control, integration of function, metabolism and growth. Nervous system, function and organisation, neurons, action potentials and synapses, sensory physiology, components of a sensation, sensory pathways, receptor classification and neural circuitry. Animal glands and secretions, types of secretion, generalized exocrine and endocrine gland structure. The endocrine system, hormonal activity, structure, mechanism of action, transport and elimination and the structure and function of key endocrine glands, motor systems that produce adaptive responses, motor organ, muscles and the neural circuits that control them, animal circulatory system, basic parts and diversity, the concept of open and closed circulation, structure of the heart, arteries, capillaries and veins and the concept of cardiovascular control, ionic and osmotic balance, osmosis / osmotic concentration and water / ion budgets and mechanisms used by invertebrates and vertebrates to respond to change in their environment, animal feeding and digestion strategies, classification of feeding mechanism, the structure and function of the generalised digestive system.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/christopher_john_roberts_cv_sept_2018.pdf</guid>
      <title>christopher_john_roberts_cv_sept_2018.pdf</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/christopher_john_roberts_cv_sept_2018.pdf</link>
      <description />
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <guid>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/evolution-and-molecular-systematics.html</guid>
      <title>Evolution Of Molecular Systematics | Christopher John Roberts</title>
      <link>http://www.christopher-john-roberts.com/science/modules-bsc/evolution-and-molecular-systematics.html</link>
      <description>Evolution and Molecular Systematics studied during Bachelor of Science Genetics and Human Health. Molecular techniques, population genetics, molecular clocks and ancestry, game theory, Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium, selection, fitness, selfish DNA, group selection, epigenetic inheritance, nucleic acid techniques including the sequencing of small sub unit ribosmal RNA, the measurement of various DNA polymorphisms via restriction fragment length polymorphisms, and the polymerase chain reaction based methods of randomly amplified polymorphic DNAs, amplified fragment length polymorphism, and microsatellites. Genetic drift, conservation, founder effect, migration and inbreeding, evolution of sex</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 04:02:00 Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
<!--<guid value="05126787-a507-4c0a-9376-21649267279e" />-->
<!--Created using XmlSitemapGenerator.org - Free HTML, RSS and XML sitemap generator-->